<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>maggick's logs - Sports</title><link href="http://matthieukeller.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://matthieukeller.com/feeds/sports.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://matthieukeller.com/</id><updated>2015-06-28T22:30:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>12 Hours swimming</title><link href="http://matthieukeller.com/2015/06/12-hours-swimming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-28T22:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-28T22:30:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Matthieu Keller</name></author><id>tag:matthieukeller.com,2015-06-28:/2015/06/12-hours-swimming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="align-left" src="/media/2015.06/swim3.jpg" alt="swiming 3" width="262"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No code this time, this article is about sport, and relate a swimming
competition.
My town organize each year a swim competition called "Les 12 heures de natation"
meaning "The 12 hours of swimming".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle is quit simple: you just swim the longest you can without "long"
stop (you can stop to drink, eat a bit and go to the toilet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I participate to this competition on the 30th May.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="align-left" src="/media/2015.06/swim3.jpg" alt="swiming 3" width="262"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No code this time, this article is about sport, and relate a swimming
competition.
My town organize each year a swim competition called "Les 12 heures de natation"
meaning "The 12 hours of swimming".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle is quit simple: you just swim the longest you can without "long"
stop (you can stop to drink, eat a bit and go to the toilet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I participate to this competition on the 30th May.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I never thought that my first sport post would be about swimming. In fact this
was my first swim competition.
Nevertheless I wanted to start this category as I do a lot of sport and
competition. In fact this kind of blog helped me to prepare for competition,
and choose my gadgets (I recently bought the Garmin Forerunner 920xt from the
advices of &lt;a href="http://dcrainmaker.com"&gt;dcrainmaker&lt;/a&gt;).
If you think this not interesting just tell me that in the comments (of course
constructive comments are better).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let start with the subject:
The beginning of the competition was Saturday 30th May at 10am. Therefore I eat
at 7am some pasta and Turkey escalope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrive with a friend and we were the first in the water, I got the cap number
1. Some guys from the staff were waiting for us to start as they count the distance
of each competitor.
The girl was there to take some photos but she head back home before I stop
swimming. I used my Garmin Forerunner 920xt to track my race (you may see the time
and distance on the watch on one of the photos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two kilometers were quit easy as this is my classic training distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="swimming 1" src="/media/2015.06/swim1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the sixth kilometres I need to go to the toilet and got a cramp
just at after putting my self out of the water at both calves. Hopefully a
life-saver was there and help me to get rid of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the 10th kilometer I was ready to stop as my goal was between 8km and 10km,
but the guy who count how much distance I swim encourage me by telling my that
the older woman in my lane was at 11km and that she was going to make 12km.
Therefore I had to make more and "Not let me beat by a woman". This was a great
advice as it motivated me to do one more kilometer. He tried the same technique
at the end of the 11th kilometer and I try to continue but after 200 meters I
feel that it would be really hard for me to continue and I stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="swimming 2" src="/media/2015.06/swim2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women within my lane were quit good. The younger one was at approximately 8
kilometer and the older on at 12km when I decided to stop at 11km. But that not
where they stop, in fact they are they are the second and the third one to the
general ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Men, 30-40 years old: 28km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Women, 30-40 years old: 22km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Women, 19-30 years old: 20km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Men, 19-30 years old: 11km (&lt;em&gt;ME !&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Men, 19-30 years old: 10km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover I am the first of my category (male, 19-30 years old).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awards were the 16th June.
And I got a beautiful basic cup!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="sports"></category><category term="swim"></category></entry></feed>